http://www.theyworkforyou.com/privacy/

Privacy Policy
TheyWorkForYou is run by the charity mySociety.
Working in the fields of transparency and accountability,
mySociety thinks hard and cares very much about the privacy and
security of our users: the length of this privacy policy is one
demonstration of that. We’ve tried, though, to keep it a clear and
reasonably quick read.
We hope it covers everything you need to know, but if you still
have any questions please feel free to contact us.
Our basic privacy policy is very simple:
We guarantee we will not sell or distribute any personal
information you share with us.
We will not send you unsolicited email.
We will gladly show you the personal data we store about you in
order to run the website.
If you’d like to know more, read on.
What information we collect and how we use it
If you sign up to receive
alert emails, we collect your email
address along with the name of the MP, postcode, or the keywords to
which you subscribe.
We’ll send you an email every time your chosen keyword/s are
spoken in a parliament or assembly we cover, or every time your
chosen MP speaks. At most (depending on how common your keyword is,
and how often your MP speaks), these will come at a frequency of one
a day and only while a parliament or assembly we cover is in session.
We may analyse alert sign-up data in aggregate, to understand
volumes and trends in what interests citizens in parliamentary
proceedings. If so, the data is anonymised, ie, stripped of all
information which would identify a specific user. Our Research Data
Release policy may be seen on request.
If you register with the site,
we collect your full name and email address, and — if you opt to
provide them — your postcode and the URL of your website.
We do not use this data for any purpose other than to allow you
to log in to the site.
If you register as a paying customer for the API,
your name, contact details, payment and security details are held
by the payment processor Stripe, whose usage terms and privacy
policy can be seen here: stripe.com/gb/privacy.
Your name, email address, the billing address of your card and the
last few digits of your card or bank account number are made
available to us along with your purchase history. We use these to
issue invoices and send you important information about changes or
updates to the service.
If you contact us by email, your
message will be accessible to our small team of support staff. We
adhere to strict internal privacy policies which may be viewed on
request.
Your personal information is never shared, or used for purposes
other than the above.
How to unsubscribe from TheyWorkForYou
email alerts
There is a link at the foot of every email we send you. Please
follow this link to pause or cancel your alerts. No log-in is
required.
If you have problems unsubscribing, you can contact us on
support@theyworkforyou.com.
How to terminate your TheyWorkForYou account
Please contact us on support@theyworkforyou.com.
Retention periods
In all cases listed above, with the exception of paying API
customers, we retain your personal data until such a time as you
unsubscribe, ask us to remove your details, or terminate your account.
We are obliged to keep records relating to financial transactions
for at least six years following the end of the accounting period in
which the transaction took place. We destroy our records after this point.
If you contact TheyWorkForYou via our support email address we
reserve the right to keep your support message for up to two years.
This is to aid continuity and so that we can view any historic
context which may have bearing on subsequent support mail, even if
members of the support staff change. Support staff adhere to internal
privacy policies which may be viewed on request.
Survey questions
In order to improve the site, we occasionally run surveys to help
us understand who uses the site and what they want. The answers are
completely anonymous, so we don’t collect any personal information.
The data may be used to inform our research.
Legal basis for processing
When you use any of the functions listed above (email alerts,
site registration or newsletters), our legal basis for processing
your personal data is legitimate interests, described in section
6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection Regulation. We believe we
have a legitimate interest in providing you with email alerts on
issues you care about being mentioned in Parliament. We believe
there is a wider societal benefit too in this greater understanding
and scrutiny of the actions of elected representatives.
For API users, our legal basis for processing information is in
the fulfillment of a contract.
Your right to access
You may contact us at any time to ask to see what personal data
we hold about you. Please contact us to request this.
Your right to object
The General Data Protection Regulation gives you the right to
object to our processing of your personal information and to ask us
to stop processing it. However, it also gives us the right to continue
to process it if we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for
the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms. To
exercise your right to object, you can contact us,
giving specific reasons why you are objecting to the processing of
your personal data. These reasons should be based upon your
particular situation.
What to do if you think we’ve mishandled your data
You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information
Commissioner’s Office. You can report a concern here
(but do contact us first, so that we can try and help).
Cookie policy
We use cookies to save you from having to repeatedly sign in to
the site, and also to remember your postcode. We may also use them
to record if you've answered one of the survey questions we ask. The
site will work with cookies disabled, but it won't be as good.
Measuring website usage (Google Analytics)
We use Google Analytics software to collect information about
how you use this site. We do this to help make sure the site is
meeting the needs of its users and to help us make improvements.
Google Analytics stores information such as what pages you visit,
how long you are on the site, how you got here, what you click on,
and information about your web browser. IP addresses are masked
(only a portion is stored) and personal information is only reported
in aggregate. We do not allow Google to use or share our analytics
data for any purpose besides providing us with analytics information,
and we recommend that any user of Google Analytics does the same.
Opting out of Google Analytics tracking
You can opt
out of Google Analytics tracking.
Network
Advertising Initiative’s opt-out form.
Rest assured, we only track usage data for one reason: to help us
understand how we can make the site work better for you, our
users.
Who we are
TheyWorkForYou is run by mySociety, a UK not-for-profit social
enterprise. Our registered address is:
…and we can also be contacted at
support@theyworkforyou.com.
TheyWorkForYou
Making it easy to keep an eye on the UK’s parliaments. Discover who represents you, how they’ve voted and what they’ve said in debates – simply and clearly.
Get insights on TheyWorkForYou and other mySociety sites, in our popular newsletter
Leave this box empty:
Your data
Help - Frequently Asked Questions
About us
Link to us
News
Privacy Policy
Source code
API
mySociety
mySociety is a registered charity in England and Wales (1076346) and a limited company (03277032). We provide commercial services through our wholly owned subsidiary SocietyWorks Ltd (05798215).
Github
Twitter
Facebook
